They Never Thought It Would Happen Again
Britannic is a action, drama, history film directed by Brian Trenchard-Smith.
It was the sister ship of the infamous Titanic...
and its final destiny was the same.
Experience the true untold story of Britannic, a tumultuous, epic voyage of human passion,
courage and betrayal aboard an ill-fated ocean liner bound for a shattering demise.
With the world at war, an undercover British agent (Amanda Ryan), embarks the Britannic
in search of a German spy believed to be on board to sabotage the ship.
Posing as a governess, the undercover agent finds herself falling
in love with the ship's chaplain (Edward Atterton).
In a stunning discovery, the lovers suddenly find themselves enemies of war.
And when a massive explosion deals a deathblow to the ship,
their battle becomes one for their own survival.
With a dynamic, international cast and a story line that hosts a chilling tale of espionage, politics and
romance, Britannic brings one of history's most devastating events to riveting, new life.
Vera Campbell, played by Amanda Ryan.
Reynolds, played by Edward Atterton.
Lady Lewis, played by Jacqueline Bisset.
Townsend, played by Ben Daniels.
Captain Barrett, played by John Rhys-Davies.
Doctor Baker, played by Bruce Payne.
Britannic is a 2000 spy television film directed by Brian Trenchard-Smith.
The film depicts a heavily fictionalized version of
the sinking of HMHS Britannic in 1916.
The film portrays a German agent sabotaging her while she is serving as a
hospital ship for the British Army during World War I.
It stars Edward Atterton and Amanda Ryan, with Jacqueline Bisset, Ben
Daniels, John Rhys-Davies, and Bruce Payne as co-stars.
It first premiered on cable network Fox Family and was then
broadcast in the United Kingdom on Channel 4.
The film explores themes of ship, world war i,
spy, shipwreck, based on true story.
The tone is emotional.